- Is everything in place? - You're not to relieve me.
- Tout est prêt ? - Tu devais pas me relayer.
I know, but I felt like taking a shift.
J'avais envie de bosser.
- You like him, don't you? - You like watching him.
T'aimes bien l'observer.
- Don't be ridiculous. - We're going to kill him.
- Dis pas de bêtises. - On va le tuer. Tu le sais ?
Morpheus believes he is the One.
Morpheus croit que c'est l'Elu.
Do you?
Et toi?
It doesn't matter what I believe.
Peu importe ce que je pense.
You don't, do you?
Tu en doutes, non ?
- Did you hear that? - Hear what?
- Tu as entendu ? - Quoi?
Are you sure this line is clean?
Cette ligne est protégée ?
Yeah, of course I'm sure.
J'en suis certain.
I better go.
J'y vais.
- Freeze! Police! - Hands on your head!
- Pas un geste ! - Mains sur la tête !
Do it! Do it now!
Vite !
- Lieutenant. - Oh, shit.
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant, you were given specific orders.
Lieutenant, vous aviez des ordres précis.
I'm just doing my job.
Je fais mon boulot.
You give me that "juris-my-dick-tion" crap, you can cram it up your ass.
Votre juridiction de mes deux, vous pouvez vous la foutre au cul !
The orders were for your protection.
Ces ordres assuraient votre protection.
I think we can handle one little girl.
Une gamine ne nous fait pas peur.
I sent two units!
J'ai envoyé deux unités.
They're bringing her down now!
Ils vont revenir avec elle.
No, lieutenant, your men are already dead.
Non, lieutenant, vos hommes sont déjà morts.
Morpheus, the line was traced. I don't know how.
Morpheus, l'appel a été intercepté.
I know. They cut the hard line.
Ils ont sectionné le câble.
There's no time. Get to another exit.
Tu dois trouver une autre issue.
- Are there any agents? - Yes.
Je suis filée ?
Goddamn it.
Merde !
You have to focus, Trinity.
Ressaisis-toi, Trinity.
There's a phone at Wells and Lake.
La cabine à l'angle de Wells et Lake.
You can make it.
Tu peux y arriver.
- All right. - Go.
- D'accord. - Vas-y.
That's impossible.
Incroyable !
Get up, Trinity. Just get up.
Relève-toi, Trinity.
Get up.
Debout !
She got out.
Elle a réussi à sortir.
It doesn't matter.
Ça ne fait rien.
- The informant is real. - Yes.
Notre informateur est fiable.
We have the name of their next target.
On a le nom de leur prochaine cible.
The name is Neo.
Il s'appelle Neo.
We'll need a search running.
Lançons les recherches.
It has already begun.
C'est déjà fait.
What?
Quoi ?
What the hell?
C'est quoi, ce truc ?
"Follow the white rabbit."
"Suis le lapin blanc."
Who is it?
Qui est-ce ?
It's Choi.
C'est Choi.
You're two hours late.
T'as deux heures de retard.
I know. It's her fault.
Je sais. C'est de sa faute.
You got the money?
T'as l'argent ?
Two grand.
2000 dollars.
Hold on.
Bouge pas.
Hallelujah.
Alléluia.
You're my savior. My own personal Jesus Christ.
T'es mon sauveur, mon petit Jésus à moi.
You get caught using that...
Si tu te fais choper...
I know. This never happened. You don't exist.
Je sais, t'existes pas.
- Right. - Something wrong, man?
- Bien. - Ça va pas ?
You look a little whiter than usual.
T'as jamais été si pâle.
My computer, it...
C'est mon ordinateur...
Ever have that feeling where you're not sure if you're awake or dreaming?
Ça t'est déjà arrivé... de confondre rêve et réalité ?
All the time. It's called mescaline.
Tout le temps. Ça s'appelle la mescaline.
It's the only way to fly.
C'est la seule façon de planer.
It just sounds like you need to unplug.
T'as l'air d'avoir besoin de déconnecter.
Get some R and R?
Faut décompresser.
What do you think, Dujour? Should we take him with us?
Qu'est-ce que t'en dis, Dujour ? On l'emmène ?
Definitely.
Absolument !
No, I can't. I have work tomorrow.
Je peux pas. Je travaille demain.
Come on.
Viens...
It'll be fun. I promise.
on va bien s'amuser. Promis.
Sure. I'll go.
C'est bon, je viens.
Hello, Neo.
Salut, Neo.
How do you know that name?
Tu connais ce nom ?
I know a lot about you.
Et bien d'autres choses.
- Who are you? - My name is Trinity.
Qui es-tu ?
The Trinity?
La fameuse Trinity ?
That cracked the IRS D-base?
Celle qui a piraté le fisc ?
That was a long time ago.
C'est du passé.
- Jesus. - What?
Nom de Dieu.
I just thought...
Je croyais...
...you were a guy.
que t'étais un mec.
Most guys do.
Comme tous les mecs.
That was you on my computer.
C'était toi sur mon ordinateur.
How did you do that?
Comment tu as fait ?
Right now, all I can tell you...
Tout ce que je peux te dire...
...is that you're in danger.
c'est que tu es en danger.
- I brought you here to warn you. - Of what?
- Je devais te prévenir. - De quoi ?
They're watching you, Neo.
Ils te surveillent.
- Who is? - Please just listen.
Qui ?
I know why you're here, Neo.
Je sais pourquoi tu es ici.
I know what you've been doing.
Je sais ce que tu fais...
I know why you hardly sleep...
pourquoi tu dors si peu...
...why you live alone and why, night after night...
pourquoi tu vis seul et pourquoi tu passes tes nuits...
...you sit at your computer.
devant ton écran.
You're looking for him.
Tu le cherches.
I know, because I was once looking for the same thing.
Je le sais, parce que je l'ai cherché aussi.
And when he found me...
Et quand il m'a trouvée...
...he told me I wasn't really looking for him...
il m'a dit que ce n'était pas lui que je cherchais...
...I was looking for an answer.
je cherchais une réponse.
It's the question that drives us, Neo.
C'est la question qui nous anime, Neo.
It's the question that brought you here.
C'est la question qui t'a amené ici.
You know the question...
Tu connais la question...
...just as I did.
comme moi.
What is the Matrix?
"Qu'est-ce que la Matrice ?"
The answer is out there, Neo.
La réponse est là-bas.
It's looking for you.
Elle te cherche.
And it will find you...
Et elle te trouvera...
...if you want it to.
si tu le désires.
Shit, shit.
Merde.
You have a problem with authority, Mr. Anderson.
L'autorité vous pose un problème.
You believe that you are special, that the rules do not apply to you.
Vous vous croyez différent, et vous enfreignez le règlement.
Obviously, you are mistaken.
Vous vous leurrez.
This is one of the top software companies in the world...
Notre entreprise est des plus performantes...
...because employees understand they are part of a whole.
car chaque employé sait qu'il fait partie d'un tout.
Thus, if an employee has a problem, the company has a problem.
Donc, si un employé a un problème, l'entreprise a un problème.
The time has come to make a choice, Mr. Anderson.
Il est temps de faire un choix, M. Anderson.
Either you choose to be at your desk on time from this day forth...
Soit vous décidez d'être à l'heure au bureau...
...or you choose to find another job.
soit vous cherchez un autre emploi.
Do I make myself clear?
Suis-je clair ?
Yes, Mr. Rhineheart. Perfectly clear.
Oui, tout à fait clair.
Yeah, that's me.
Oui, c'est moi.
Have a nice day.
Bonne journée.
Hello, Neo. Do you know who this is?
Neo, sais-tu qui je suis ?
- Morpheus. - Yes.
Morpheus.
I've been looking for you.
Je te cherchais, Neo.
I don't know if you're ready to see what I want to show you.
J'ignore si tu es prêt à voir ce que je veux te montrer...
But unfortunately, you and I have run out of time.
mais malheureusement, le temps nous est compté.
They're coming for you, and I don't know what they're going to do.
Ils viennent te chercher. J'ignore ce qu'ils vont faire.
Who's coming for me?
Qui vient me chercher ?
Stand up and see for yourself.
Lève-toi et tu le sauras.
What? Right now?
Maintenant ?
Yes. Now.
Oui.
Do it slowly.
Lève-toi lentement.
The elevator.
L'ascenseur.
- Oh, shit! - Yes.
Bon sang !
What do they want?
Que veulent-ils ?
I don't know. If you don't want to find out, get out of there.
Je ne sais pas. Si tu ne veux pas le savoir, sors d'ici.
I can guide you, but you must do exactly as I say.
Suis mes indications à la lettre.
- But what if they... - Go. Now.
Vas-y ! Maintenant !
Stay here for just a moment.
Reste là un moment.
When I tell you, go to the end of the row...
Quand je te le dirai, gagne le bureau...
...to the office at the end of the hall.
qui se trouve au bout du couloir.
Stay as low as you can.
Reste accroupi.
Go. Now.
Vas-y.
Good. Now, outside there is a scaffold.
Bien. Dehors, il y a un échafaudage.
- How do you know this? - We don't have time.
- Comment tu le sais ? - Le temps presse.
To your left there's a window. Go to it.
Va à la fenêtre sur ta gauche.
Open it.
Ouvre-la.
Take the scaffold to the roof.
Grimpe sur le toit.
No way! No way! This is crazy!
Pas question ! C'est de la folie !
There are two ways out of this building.
Tu as deux portes de sortie.
One is that scaffold. The other is in their custody.
Ou l'échafaudage, ou tu te fais arrêter.
You take a chance either way. I leave it to you.
Les deux sont risqués. A toi de choisir.
This is insane!
C'est insensé !
Why is this happening to me?
Pourquoi moi ?
What'd I do?
Qu'est-ce que j'ai fait ?
I'm nobody. I didn't do anything.
Je ne suis personne. J'ai rien fait.
I'm gonna die.
Je vais mourir.
I can't do this.
J'y arriverai jamais.
Shit.
Merde.
As you can see, we've had our eye on you for some time now, Mr. Anderson.
Comme vous le voyez, nous avons l'oeil sur vous depuis quelque temps.
It seems that you've been living...
Il semble que vous menez...
...two lives.
une double vie.
In one life, you're Thomas A. Anderson...
Dans l'une, vous êtes Thomas Anderson...
...program writer for a respectable software company.
programmeur dans une entreprise de logiciels.
You have a social security number. You pay your taxes.
Vous êtes assuré social, vous payez vos impôts...
And you...
et vous...
...help your landlady carry out her garbage.
aidez la concierge à sortir les poubelles.
The other life is lived in computers...
L'autre vie est consacrée aux ordinateurs.
...where you go by the hacker alias "Neo"...
Votre nom d'emprunt de pirate est Neo...
...and are guilty of virtually every computer crime we have a law for.
et vous avez commis presque tous les crimes informatiques.
One of these lives...
Une de ces deux vies...
...has a future.
a un avenir.
And one of them does not.
Et l'autre n'en a pas.
I'm going to be as forthcoming as I can be, Mr. Anderson.
Je vais aller droit au but, M. Anderson.
You're here...
Vous êtes ici...
...because we need your help.
car nous avons besoin de vous.
We know that you've been contacted by a certain...
Nous savons que vous avez été contacté...
...individual.
par un individu...
A man who calls himself "Morpheus."
qui se fait appeler Morpheus.
Whatever you think you know about this man is irrelevant.
Ce que vous pensez de lui n'entre pas en ligne de compte.
He is considered by many authorities...
Les autorités tiennent cet homme...
...to be the most dangerous man alive.
pour le plus dangereux au monde.
My colleagues...
Mes collègues...
...believe that I am wasting my time with you.
pensent que je perds mon temps avec vous.
But I believe you wish to do the right thing.
Mais je crois que vous souhaitez coopérer.
We're willing to wipe the slate clean...
Nous sommes prêts à passer l'éponge...
...give you a fresh start.
et à vous laisser repartir à zéro.
All we're asking in return is your cooperation...
En échange, nous sollicitons votre aide...
...in bringing a known terrorist to justice.
afin de traduire ce terroriste en justice.
That sounds like a really good deal.
C'est une proposition honnête.
But I got a better one.
Mais j'en ai une meilleure.
How about...
Voilà...
...I give you the finger...
je vous envoie vous faire foutre...
...and you give me my phone call.
et vous me laissez téléphoner.
Mr. Anderson...
Eh bien, M. Anderson...
...you disappoint me.
vous me décevez.
You can't scare me with this gestapo crap.
Vos méthodes fachos ne m'effraient pas.
I know my rights.
Je connais mes droits.
I want my phone call.
Je veux téléphoner.
Tell me, Mr. Anderson...
Dites-moi, M. Anderson...
...what good is a phone call...
à quoi bon téléphoner...
...if you're unable to speak?
si vous ne pouvez pas parler ?
You're going to help us, Mr. Anderson...
Vous allez nous aider...
...whether you want to or not.
que vous le vouliez...
This line is tapped, so I must be brief.
La ligne est sur écoute. Je serai bref.
They got to you first, but they've underestimated how important you are.
Ils t'ont appréhendé avant nous, mais ils t'ont sous-estimé.
If they knew what I know...
S'ils savaient ce que je sais...
...you would probably be dead.
tu serais mort.
What are you talking about? What is happening to me?
Qu'est-ce que tu racontes ? Que m'arrive-t-il ?
You are the One, Neo. You may have spent the last few years...
Tu es l'Elu, Neo. Tu m'as cherché pendant des années.
...looking for me, but I've spent my entire life...
Moi, j'ai passé ma vie...
...looking for you.
à te chercher.
Now, do you still want to meet?
Veux-tu toujours me rencontrer ?
- Yes. - Then go to the Adams Street bridge.
- Oui. - Va sous le pont, rue Adams.
Get in.
Monte.
What's this?
Pourquoi ?
It's necessary, Neo. For our protection.
C'est primordial...pour se protéger.
- From what? - From you.
De quoi ?
- Take off your shirt. - What?
Enlève ta chemise.
Stop the car.
Arrête la voiture.
Listen, coppertop.
Ecoute, pile sèche.
We don't have time for 20 Questions.
Je joue pas aux devinettes.
Right now, there's only one rule:
Le principe est le suivant :
Our way...
tu obéis...
...or the highway.
ou tu déguerpis.
Fine.
Entendu.
Please, Neo, you have to trust me.
S'il te plaît, fais-moi confiance.
- Why? - Because you have been down there.
- Pourquoi ? - Tu sais de quoi il retourne.
You know that road.
Tu connais cette route.
You know exactly where it ends.
Tu sais où elle mène.
And I know that's not where you want to be.
Et tu ne veux pas y aller.
Apoc, lights.
Apoc, lumière !
- Lie back. - Lift up your shirt.
Allonge-toi. Soulève ta chemise.
- What's that? - You're bugged.
C'est quoi ?
Try and relax.
Détends-toi.
Come on.
Amène-toi.
It's on the move.
Il se déplace.
Come on, you shit.
Saleté.
- You're gonna lose it. - No, I'm not.
- Tu vas le perdre. - Mais non.
Clear!
Ecartez-vous !
Jesus Christ! That thing's real!?
Nom de Dieu, c'était vrai !
This is it.
On est arrivés.
Let me give you one piece of advice.
Je vais te donner un conseil.
Be honest.
Sois franc.
He knows more than you can imagine.
Il en sait plus que tu ne crois.
At last.
Enfin !
Welcome, Neo.
Bienvenue, Neo.
As you no doubt have guessed...
Comme tu as dû le deviner...
...I am Morpheus.
je suis Morpheus.
It's an honor to meet you.
Je suis très honoré.
No...
Non...
...the honor is mine.
tout l'honneur est pour moi.
Please, come. Sit.
Je t'en prie, viens t'asseoir.
I imagine...
Je suppose...
...that right now you're feeling a bit like Alice...
que tu éprouves la même chose qu'Alice...
...tumbling down the rabbit hole?
dans le terrier du lapin.
You could say that.
C'est un peu ça.
I can see it in your eyes.
Je le lis dans tes yeux.
You have the look of a man who accepts what he sees...
Tu as le regard d'un homme qui croit ce qu'il voit...
...because he's expecting to wake up.
parce qu'il s'attend à se réveiller.
Ironically, this is not far from the truth.
On n'est pas loin de la vérité.
Do you believe in fate, Neo?
Crois-tu au destin, Neo ?
No.
Non.
Why not?
Pourquoi pas ?
I don't like the idea that I'm not in control of my life.
J'aime savoir que je dirige ma vie.
I know exactly what you mean.
Je comprends très bien ce que tu veux dire.
Let me tell you why you're here.
Sais-tu pourquoi tu es ici ?
You know something.
Tu sais quelque chose.
What you know, you can't explain.
Tu ne te l'expliques pas...
But you feel it.
mais tu le ressens.
You felt it your entire life:
Tu as toujours ressenti...
Something's wrong with the world. You don't know what, but it's there.
que le monde ne tournait pas rond. C'est en toi...
Like a splinter in your mind...
comme une écharde dans ton esprit.
...driving you mad.
Ça te rend fou.
It is this feeling that has brought you to me.
C'est cela qui t'a mené jusqu'à moi.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
Sais-tu de quoi je parle ?
The Matrix?
De la Matrice.
Do you want to know...
Veux-tu savoir...
...what it is?
ce que c'est ?
The Matrix is everywhere.
La Matrice est omniprésente.
It is all around us.
Elle nous enveloppe...
Even now, in this very room.
même dans cette pièce.
You can see it when you look out your window...
Tu peux la voir de ta fenêtre...
...or when you turn on your television.
ou quand tu allumes la télévision.
You can feel it when you go to work...
Tu sens sa présence quand tu pars travailler...
...when you go to church...
quand tu vas à l'église...
...when you pay your taxes.
quand tu paies tes impôts.
It is the world that has been pulled over your eyes...
C'est le monde qu'ils ont mis devant tes yeux...
...to blind you from the truth.
pour te cacher la vérité.
What truth?
Quelle vérité ?
That you are a slave.
Tu es un esclave, Neo.
Like everyone else, you were born into bondage...
Tu es né en captivité...
...born into a prison that you cannot smell or taste or touch.
dans une prison que tu ne peux ni sentir, ni toucher.
A prison...
Une prison...
...for your mind.
pour ton esprit.
Unfortunately, no one can be...
Malheureusement, il est impossible...
...told what the Matrix is.
de te définir la Matrice.
You have to see it for yourself.
Tu devras la percer à jour.
This is your last chance.
C'est ta dernière opportunité.
After this, there is no turning back.
Tu ne pourras pas rebrousser chemin.
You take the blue pill...
Si tu choisis la bleue...
...the story ends, you wake up in your bed and believe...
tout s'arrête. Tu te réveilles dans ton lit et tu crois...
...whatever you want to believe.
ce que bon te semble.
You take the red pill...
Si tu prends la rouge...
...you stay in Wonderland...
tu restes aux Pays des Merveilles...
...and I show you how deep the rabbit hole goes.
et je t'emmène au tréfonds du terrier.
Remember...
Souviens-toi...
...all I'm offering is the truth. Nothing more.
je ne t'offre que la vérité. Rien de plus.
Follow me.
Suis-moi.
Apoc, are we on-line?
Apoc, on est connectés ?
Almost.
Presque.
Time is always against us.
Le temps joue contre nous.
Please take a seat there.
Assieds-toi là.
You did all this?
Tu as fait tout ça ?
The pill you took is part of a trace program.
La pilule est un traceur.
It disrupts your carrier signals so we can pinpoint your location.
Elle dérègle tes signaux d'entrée et de sortie pour qu'on te localise.
What does that mean?
Comment ça ?
It means buckle your seat belt, Dorothy...
Mets ta ceinture, Dorothy...
...because Kansas...
et dis adieu...
...is going bye-bye.
au Kansas.
Did you...?
Vous avez...
Have you ever had a dream, Neo, that you were so sure was real?
As-tu déjà fait un rêve qui te semblait vrai ?
What if you were unable to wake from that dream?
Si tu ne sortais plus de ce rêve...
How would you know the difference between the dream world...
comment distinguerais-tu le rêve...
...and the real world?
de la réalité ?
This can't be.
Ça ne peut pas l'être.
Be what?
Quoi ?
Be real?
Etre vrai ?
- Going into replication. - Apoc?
Reproduction !
Still nothing.
- Apoc ? - Toujours rien.
It's cold!
C'est froid.
Tank, we'll need a signal soon.
Il nous faut un signal.
- I got a fibrillation. - Apoc, location.
Fibrillation.
Targeting almost there.
Objectif presque atteint.
He's going into arrest.
Il va y rester.
- Lock. I got him! - Now, Tank, now!
Verrouillage !
Welcome...
Bienvenue...
...to the real world.
dans le monde réel.
We've done it, Trinity.
Nous avons réussi.
We found him.
Nous l'avons trouvé.
- I hope you're right. - I don't have to hope.
- Espérons-le. - Je n'espère pas.
I know it.
J'en suis sûr.
Am I dead?
Je suis mort ?
Far from it.
Bien au contraire.
He still needs a lot of work.
Il faut le rééduquer.
What are you doing?
Que faites-vous ?
Your muscles atrophied. We're rebuilding them.
Nous renforçons tes muscles.
Why do my eyes hurt?
J'ai mal aux yeux.
You've never used them before.
Ils n'ont jamais servi.
Rest, Neo.
Repose-toi.
The answers are coming.
Les réponses vont venir.
Morpheus, what's happened to me?
Que m'est-il arrivé ?
What is this place?
Où sommes-nous ?
More important than "what" is "when."
Demande plutôt "quelle année".
"When"?
Quelle année ?
You believe it's the year 1999...
Tu crois être en 1999.
...when in fact, it's closer to 2199.
En fait, on approche de 2199.
I can't tell you exactly what year it is...
Je ne peux pas spécifier l'année...
...because we honestly don't know.
parce que nous l'ignorons.
There's nothing I can say that will explain it for you.
Rien de ce que je dirai ne t'éclairera davantage.
Come with me. See for yourself.
Viens avec moi.
This is my ship.
C'est mon vaisseau.
The Nebuchadnezzar. It's a hovercraft.
Le Nebuchadnezzar. C'est un aéroglisseur.
This is the main deck.
On est sur le pont principal.
This is the core...
Le noyau...
...where we broadcast our pirate signal and hack into the Matrix.
où nous émettons notre signal et piratons la Matrice.
Most of my crew you already know.
L'équipage, tu le connais déjà.
This is Apoc...
Je te présente Apoc...
...Switch...
Switch...
- ...and Cypher. - Hi.
et Cypher.
The ones you don't know: Tank and his big brother, Dozer.
Ceux que tu ne connais pas : Tank et son grand frère, Dozer.
The little one behind you is Mouse.
Le petit, derrière toi, c'est Mouse.
You wanted to know what the Matrix is?
Tu voulais savoir ce qu'est la Matrice ?
Try to relax.
Détends-toi.
This will feel a little weird.
C'est une drôle de sensation.
This...
Ça...
...is the Construct.
c'est la Structure...
It's our loading program.
notre programme de chargement.
We can load anything, from clothing...
On y met ce qu'on veut. Des vêtements...
...to equipment...
du matériel...
...weapons...
des armes...
...training simulations...
des simulations d'entraînement...
...anything we need.
tout ce dont nous avons besoin.
Right now we're inside a computer program?
On est dans l'ordinateur ?
Is it really so hard to believe?
C'est si difficile à croire ?
Your clothes are different. The plugs in your body are gone.
Tu es vêtu autrement, tu es déconnecté.
Your hair has changed.
Ta coiffure n'est pas la même.
Your appearance now is what we call "residual self-image."
Tu n'es qu'une "image intérieure résiduelle".
It is the mental projection of your digital self.
La projection mentale de ton moi digital.
This isn't real?
Tout ça n'est pas réel ?
What is "real"?
Qu'est-ce que le réel ?
How do you define "real"?
Comment le définis-tu ?
If you're talking about what you can feel...
Si tu fais allusion au toucher...
...what you can smell, taste and see...
à l'odorat, au goût et à la vue...
...then "real" is simply electrical signals interpreted by your brain.
alors le réel n'est qu'un signal interprété par ton cerveau.
This is the world that you know.
Ça, c'est le monde que tu connais.
The world as it was at the end of the 20th century.
Tel qu'il était à la fin du XXème siècle.
It exists now only as part of a neural-interactive simulation...
Il fait partie de la simulation neuro-interactive...
...that we call the Matrix.
appelée la Matrice.
You've been living in a dream world, Neo.
Tu as vécu dans un monde imaginaire.
This is the world...
Voici le monde...
...as it exists today.
tel qu'il est aujourd'hui.
Welcome to "the desert...
Bienvenue dans "le désert...
...of the real."
de la réalité".
We have only bits and pieces of information.
On n'a que des bribes d'information.
But what we know for certain is that in the early 21 st century...
Mais on est sûrs qu'au début du XXlème siècle...
...all of mankind was united in celebration.
l'humanité tout entière célébrait son unité.
We marveled at our own magnificence as we gave birth to AI.
On s'extasiait devant notre propre magnificence, car on avait généré l'I.A.
You mean artificial intelligence.
L'intelligence artificielle ?
A singular consciousness that spawned an entire race of machines.
Une conscience phénoménale qui a engendré une génération de machines.
We don't know who struck first, us or them.
On ne sait pas qui a frappé le premier.
But we know that it was us that scorched the sky.
Mais nous avons embrasé le ciel.
They were dependent on solar power...
A l'époque, l'énergie solaire assurait leur survie.
...and it was believed that they would be unable to survive...
On croyait qu'elles mourraient...
...without an energy source as abundant as the sun.
privées de cette source d'énergie si riche.
Throughout human history, we have been dependent on machines to survive.
De tout temps, les machines nous ont permis de survivre.
Fate, it seems, is not without a sense of irony.
Il semblerait que le destin ne manque pas d'ironie.
The human body generates more bioelectricity than a 120-volt battery.
L'homme génère plus de bioélectricité qu'une batterie de 120 volts...
And over 25,000 BTUs of body heat.
et plus de 25 000 calories en chaleur corporelle.
Combined with a form of fusion...
En associant l'homme à une forme de fusion...
...the machines had found all the energy they would ever need.
les machines avaient trouvé plus d'énergie qu'il ne leur en fallait.
There are fields, Neo, endless fields...
Il y a des champs, à perte de vue...
...where human beings are no longer born.
où les êtres humains ne naissent plus.
We are grown.
Nous sommes cultivés.
For the longest time, I wouldn't believe it.
Je refusais d'y croire.
And then I saw the fields with my own eyes...
Et puis, j'ai vu ces champs de mes propres yeux.
...watched them liquefy the dead...
Elles liquéfiaient les morts...
...so they could be fed intravenously to the living.
pour les injecter aux vivants.
And standing there, facing the pure, horrifying precision...
Et là, devant cette absolue et monstrueuse ingéniosité...
...I came to realize the obviousness of the truth.
j'ai enfin admis l'indéniable vérité.
What is the Matrix?
Qu'est-ce que la Matrice ?
Control.
Le contrôle.
The Matrix is a computer-generated dream world...
La Matrice est un monde virtuel...
...built to keep us under control...
créé pour mieux nous maîtriser...
...in order to change a human being...
afin de transformer l'être humain...
...into this.
en ceci.
No.
Non.
I don't believe it.
Je n'y crois pas.
It's not possible.
C'est impossible.
I didn't say it would be easy, Neo. I just said it would be the truth.
Je n'ai pas dit que ce serait facile. J'ai dit que ce serait la vérité.
Let me out!
Laisse-moi sortir !
Let me out! I want out!
Je veux sortir !
- Easy, Neo. Easy. - Get this thing out of me.
- Calme-toi. - Enlevez-moi ce truc.
Get this thing out of me!
Enlevez-moi ça !
Don't touch me!
Me touchez pas.
Stay away from me!
N'approchez pas.
I don't believe it.
Je vous crois pas.
- He's gonna pop. - Breathe, Neo.
- Il va lâcher. - Respire !
Just breathe.
Respire.
I can't go back, can I?
Je peux pas rentrer ?
No.
Non.
But if you could...
Mais si tu le pouvais...
...would you really want to?
le voudrais-tu vraiment ?
I owe you an apology.
Je te dois des excuses.
We have a rule.
Nous avons pour règle...
We never free a mind once it's reached a certain age.
de ne jamais libérer un esprit après un certain âge.
It's dangerous.
C'est risqué.
The mind has trouble letting go.
L'esprit ne lâche pas prise.
I've seen it before, and I'm sorry.
C'est déjà arrivé. Je suis désolé.
I did what I did because...
Je l'ai fait parce que...
...I had to.
il le fallait.
When the Matrix was first built, there was a man born inside...
A la création de la Matrice, un homme est né à l'intérieur...
...who had the ability to change whatever he wanted...
qui avait la faculté de changer ce qu'il voulait...
...to remake the Matrix as he saw fit.
et de l'ajuster comme il l'entendait.
It was he who freed the first of us...
C'est lui qui a libéré le premier d'entre nous...
...taught us the truth.
et nous a révélé la vérité.
As long as the Matrix exists...
Tant que la Matrice existera...
...the human race will never be free.
l'humanité ne sera pas libre.
After he died...
Après sa mort...
...the Oracle prophesied his return...
l'Oracle a prophétisé son retour.
...and that his coming would hail the destruction of the Matrix...
Sa venue annoncerait la fin de la Matrice...
...end the war...
mettrait un terme à la guerre...
...bring freedom to our people.
et nous libérerait.
That is why there are those of us who spent our lives searching the Matrix...
C'est pourquoi certains passent leur vie à explorer la Matrice...
...looking for him.
pour trouver cet homme.
I did what I did because...
J'ai fait ce que j'ai fait car...
...I believe that search is over.
je crois l'avoir trouvé.
Get some rest.
Repose-toi.
You're going to need it.
Tu en auras besoin.
For what?
Pour quoi ?
Your training.
Ton entraînement.
Morning. Did you sleep?
Bonjour. Tu as dormi ?
You will tonight.
Tu dormiras ce soir.
I guarantee it.
C'est sûr.
I'm Tank. I'll be your operator.
Tank, ton opérateur.
- You don't have any... - Holes? Nope.
- Tu n'as pas de... - De trous ? Non.
Me and my brother, Dozer, are 100% pure, old-fashioned, homegrown human.
Mon frère et moi, on est des vrais de vrai, faits maison, à l'ancienne.
Born free right here...
Nés libres...
...in the real world.
dans le monde réel.
Genuine child of Zion.
Fils authentiques de Zion.
- Zion? - If the war was over tomorrow...
- Zion ? - Si on gagnait la guerre...
...Zion's where the party would be.
on y ferait la teuf.
It's a city?
C'est une ville ?
The last human city. The only place we have left.
La dernière peuplée d'êtres humains.
Where is it?
Où est-elle ?
Deep underground near the Earth's core, where it's still warm.
Tout au fond...
You live long enough, you might see it.
Si tu vis vieux, tu la verras.
Goddamn! I gotta tell you, I'm excited to see what you're capable of...
Je vais te dire, ça me démange de savoir...
...if Morpheus is right and all.
si Morpheus a vu juste.
We're not supposed to talk about this, but...
On doit pas en parler, mais...
...if you are...
si c'est bien toi...
...it's a very exciting time.
Quel moment excitant !
We got a lot to do. We gotta get to it.
On a du pain sur la planche. On s'y met.
We're supposed to start with these programs first.
On doit faire les programmes d'opération.
That's major boring shit. Let's do something more fun.
C'est chiant. Faisons un truc plus marrant.
How about...
Ça te dirait...
...combat training?
de t'entraîner au combat ?
"Jujitsu"?
Jiu-jitsu ?
I'm going to learn jujitsu?
Je vais apprendre le jiu-jitsu ?
Holy shit!
Merde alors !
"Hey, Mikey, I think he likes it."
On dirait que ça lui plaît.
How about some more?
T'en veux encore ?
Hell, yes.
Envoie la purée.
How is he?
Il s'en sort bien ?
Ten hours straight. He's a machine.
10 heures non-stop ! Une machine !
I know kung fu.
Je connais le kung-fu.
Show me.
Montre-moi.
This is a sparring program...
Ce programme de combat...
...similar to the programmed reality of the Matrix.
s'inspire de la réalité virtuelle de la Matrice.
It has the same basic rules. Like gravity.
Il obéit aux mêmes lois. Comme la pesanteur.
These rules are no different than those of a computer system.
On les retrouve dans le système informatique.
Some of them can be bent.
On peut en enfreindre certaines...
Others can be broken.
et en violer...
Understand?
C'est clair ?
Then hit me...
Frappe-moi...
...if you can.
si tu peux.
Adaptation.
Adaptation...
Improvisation.
improvisation.
But your weakness...
Mais ton point faible...
...is not your technique.
n'est pas la technique.
Morpheus is fighting Neo.
Morpheus combat Neo.
How did I beat you?
Pourquoi ai-je gagné ?
You're too fast.
Tu es très rapide.
Do you believe that...
Penses-tu que...
...my being stronger or faster...
ma force ou ma rapidité...
...has anything to do with my muscles in this place?
puisse avoir un rapport avec mes muscles dans ce lieu ?
You think you're breathing air?
Tu crois respirer de l'air ?
Again!
De nouveau !
Jesus Christ, he's fast!
Nom de Dieu, ce qu'il est rapide.
His neuro-kinetics are way above normal.
Sa neuro-cinétique explose.
What are you waiting for?
Qu'est-ce que tu attends ?
You're faster than this.
Tu es bien plus rapide.
Don't think you are.
Ne le pense pas.
Know you are.
Prends-en conscience.
Come on! Stop trying to hit me, and hit me!
N'essaie pas de me frapper, frappe-moi.
I don't believe it.
Incroyable !
I know what you're trying to do.
Je sais où tu veux en venir.
I'm trying to free your mind, Neo.
J'essaie de libérer ton esprit.
But I can only show you the door.
Je peux juste te montrer la porte.
You have to walk through it.
A toi de la franchir.
Tank, load the jump program.
Tank, charge le programme de sauts.
You have to let it all go, Neo. Fear...
Tu dois te délivrer de tout. De la peur...
...doubt and disbelief.
du doute, et du scepticisme.
Free your mind.
Libère ton esprit.
Okey-dokey.
Ouais, d'accord.
Free my mind.
Libérer mon esprit.
What if he makes it?
S'il y arrivait ?
- No one's ever made their first jump. - I know.
- Pas la première fois. - Je sais.
- But what if he does? - He won't.
- Et s'il réussissait ? - Impossible.
Come on.
Allez !
All right.
Très bien.
No problem. Free my mind.
Tout va bien. Me libérer l'esprit.
Free my mind. No problem. Right.
Pas de problème.
What does that mean?
Qu'est-ce que ça signifie ?
It doesn't mean anything.
Ça ne signifie rien.
Everybody falls the first time.
Tout le monde tombe la première fois.
Right, Trin?
Pas vrai, Trin ?
- I thought it wasn't real. - Your mind makes it real.
- C'était pas irréel ? - Pas pour ton esprit.
If you're killed in the Matrix...
Si on est tué dans la Matrice...
...you die here?
on meurt ici ?
The body cannot live without the mind.
Corps et esprit ne font qu'un.
I don't remember you ever bringing me dinner.
Tu ne m'as jamais apporté mon dîner.
There is something about him, isn't there?
Quelque chose émane de lui, non ?
You're a believer now?
Tu es devenu croyant ?
I keep wondering...
Je me demande...
...if Morpheus is so sure, why not take him to see the Oracle?
Si Morpheus en est sûr, pourquoi ne pas l'emmener voir l'Oracle ?
Morpheus will take him when he's ready.
Morpheus attend qu'il soit prêt.
The Matrix is a system, Neo.
La Matrice est un système.
That system is our enemy.
Il est notre ennemi.
But when you're inside, what do you see?
Qu'y a-t-il à l'intérieur ?
Businessmen, teachers, lawyers, carpenters.
Des hommes d'affaires, des professeurs, des avocats, des charpentiers.
The very minds of the people we are trying to save.
Des esprits qu'on tente de sauver.
But until we do, these people are a part of that system...
En attendant, ils font partie de ce système...
...and that makes them our enemy.
et cela en fait nos ennemis.
You have to understand...
Tu dois comprendre...
...most of these people are not ready to be unplugged.
Ils ne supporteraient pas d'être débranchés.
And many of them are so inert...
Certains sont si amorphes...
...so hopelessly dependent on the system...
et tellement dépendants du système...
...that they will fight to protect it.
qu'ils se battraient pour le protéger.
Were you listening to me or looking at the woman in the red dress?
Tu m'écoutais, Neo ? Tu regardais la femme en rouge.
Freeze it.
Arrêt sur image.
- This isn't the Matrix? - No.
On n'est pas dans la Matrice ?
It's another training program designed to teach you one thing:
Ce programme a été créé pour t'enseigner une chose.
If you are not one of us, you are one of them.
Tu es soit avec nous, soit avec eux.
- What are they? - Sentient programs.
- Que sont-ils ? - Des programmes sensoriels.
They can move in and out of any software still hardwired to their system.
Ils entrent et sortent des logiciels reliés à leur système.
That means that anyone we haven't unplugged...
Toute personne qui n'est pas débranchée...
...is potentially an agent.
est un agent en puissance.
Inside the Matrix...
Dans la Matrice...
...they are everyone...
ils sont tout le monde...
...and they are no one.
et personne.
We have survived by hiding and running from them...
On a survécu en les fuyant.
...but they are the gatekeepers.
Mais ils sont les gardiens.
They're guarding all the doors and holding all the keys.
Ils détiennent les clefs des portes.
Sooner or later, someone will have to fight them.
Tôt ou tard, quelqu'un devra les combattre.
Someone?
Quelqu'un...
I won't lie to you, Neo.
Je serai franc.
Every single man or woman who has fought an agent, has died.
Tous les humains qui se sont battus avec un agent, sont morts.
But where they have failed, you will succeed.
Là où ils ont échoué, tu réussiras.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
I've seen an agent punch through a concrete wall.
Ils éventrent un mur d'un coup de poing.
Men have emptied entire clips at them and hit nothing but air.
On leur tire dessus, ils esquivent les balles.
Yet their strength and speed are still based in a world built on rules.
Malgré tout, leur force et leur rapidité reposent sur des lois.
Because of that...
C'est pour ça...
...they will never be as strong or as fast as you can be.
qu'ils ne seront jamais aussi forts et aussi rapides que toi.
What are you telling me?
Que veux-tu dire ?
That I can dodge bullets?
Je peux esquiver des balles ?
No, Neo.
Non, Neo.
I'm trying to tell you that when you're ready...
Sache que lorsque tu seras prêt...
...you won't have to.
ce sera inutile.
We got trouble.
Des ennuis !
- Did Zion send the warning? - No, another ship.
Zion l'a signalé ?
Shit.
Merde.
- Squiddy's sweeping in quick. - Squiddy?
La pieuvre a mis le turbo.
A sentinel. A killing machine designed for one thing.
Une sentinelle, conçue dans un seul but.
Search and destroy.
Chercher, détruire.
Set her down there.
Posons-nous ici.
How are we doing, Tank?
Où tu en es ?
Power off-line.
Courant coupé.
EMP armed...
BEM chargé...
- ...and ready. - EMP?
et paré à tirer.
Electromagnetic pulse.
Booster Electro-Magnétique.
Disables any electrical system in the blast radius.
Il anéantit les systèmes électriques.
It's the only weapon we have against the machines.
La seule arme contre les machines.
- Where are we? - Their old service and waste systems.
On est où ?
Sewers.
Les égouts.
There used to be cities that spanned hundreds of miles.
Il y avait des villes à perte de vue.
Now these sewers are all that's left.
Il n'en reste que les égouts.
Quiet.
Silence !
You scared the bejesus out of me.
Tu m'as fichu la trouille !
- Sorry. - It's okay.
- Désolé. - C'est pas grave.
Is that...?
C'est...
The Matrix?
La Matrice ?
- Do you always look at it encoded? - Well, you have to.
- Tu la regardes codée ? - Bien obligé.
The image translators work for the construct program.
Les décodeurs d'images travaillent pour la Structure.
But there's way too much information to decode the Matrix.
Il y a trop de données pour décoder la Matrice.
You get used to it. I don't even see the code.
On s'y fait. Je vois même plus le code.
All I see is blonde, brunette, redhead.
Je vois des blondes, des rousses...
Do you...
Tu veux...
...want a drink?
boire un coup ?
Sure.
D'accord.
You know...
Je sais...
...I know what you're thinking.
ce que tu penses...
Because right now I'm thinking the same thing.
parce que je pense comme toi.
Actually, I've been thinking it ever since I got here.
J'y pense depuis que je suis ici.
Why, oh, why didn't I take the blue pill?
Pourquoi j'ai pas pris la pilule bleue ?
Good shit, huh?
Pas dégueu, hein ?
Dozer makes it.
Dozer fait ça.
It's good for two things:
Ça sert à deux choses :
Degreasing engines and killing brain cells.
dégraisser les moteurs, et tuer les cellules grises.
So can I ask you something?
Je peux te poser une question ?
Did he tell you why he did it?
Il t'a dit pourquoi il l'a fait ?
Why you're here?
Pourquoi t'es là ?
Jesus!
Bon sang.
What a mind job.
Tu dois cogiter.
So you're here to save the world.
Tu viens sauver le monde.
What do you say to something like that?
Qu'est-ce que tu dis de ça ?
A little piece of advice.
Un petit conseil...
You see an agent...
Si tu vois un agent...
...you do what we do:
fais comme nous...
Run.
cours !
You run your ass off.
Prends la tangente !
Thanks for the drink.
Merci pour le verre.
Sweet dreams.
Fais de beaux rêves.
Do we have a deal, Mr. Reagan?
Marché conclu, M. Reagan ?
You know...
Vous savez...
...I know this steak doesn't exist.
je sais que ce steak n'existe pas.
I know that when I put it in my mouth...
Lorsque je le mets en bouche...
...the Matrix is telling my brain that it is...
la Matrice dit à mon cerveau qu'il est...
...juicy...
tendre...
...and delicious.
et savoureux.
After nine years...
Au bout de 9 ans...
...you know what I realize?
j'ai compris une chose.
Ignorance is bliss.
"Qui ne sait rien..."
Then we have a deal.
Alors, nous sommes d'accord.
I don't want to remember nothing.
Je ne veux me souvenir de rien.
Nothing. You understand?
De rien !
And I want to be rich.
Et je veux être riche.
You know, someone important.
Je veux être quelqu'un d'important...
Like an actor.
un acteur, par exemple.
Whatever you want, Mr. Reagan.
Tout ce que vous voudrez, M. Reagan.
You get my body back in a power plant...
Renvoyez mon corps au groupe générateur...
...reinsert me into the Matrix...
réintégrez-moi dans la Matrice...
...I'll get you what you want.
et je dirai tout.
Access codes to the Zion mainframe.
Les codes d'accès de Zion.
No. I told you, I don't know them.
Je vous l'ai dit, je les sais pas.
I can get you the man who does.
Je vous donnerai l'homme qui les sait.
Morpheus.
Morpheus.
Here you go, buddy. Breakfast of champions.
Le petit-déj des champions !
Close your eyes, it feels like you're eating runny eggs.
Les yeux fermés, on dirait un oeuf à la coque.
Or a bowl of snot.
Ou un bol de morve.
You know what it reminds me of?
Ça me rappelle...
Tastee Wheat. Did you ever eat Tastee Wheat?
les germes de blé. T'en as mangé ?
No, but technically, neither did you.
Ni toi, techniquement.
That's exactly my point. Exactly.
C'est là où je veux en venir.
Because you have to wonder...
Ça m'intrigue...
...how do the machines really know what Tastee Wheat tasted like?
Comment les machines connaissent le goût du blé ?
Maybe they got it wrong.
Si elles se gouraient ?
Maybe what I think Tastee Wheat tasted like, actually tasted like...
Ce que je crois être le goût du blé est le goût...
...oatmeal or tuna fish.
de l'avoine ou du thon.
That makes you wonder. Take chicken, for example.
Ça donne à réfléchir. Exemple : le poulet.
Maybe they didn't know what to make it taste like...
Elles en ignoraient le goût...
...which is why it tastes like everything.
c'est pour ça que c'est fadasse.
- And maybe they... - Shut up.
Ferme-la !
It's a single-celled protein...
Cette protéine unicellulaire...
...combined with synthetic aminos, vitamins and minerals.
est mélangée à des aminoacides.
Everything the body needs.
Tout ce dont ton corps a besoin.
It doesn't have everything the body needs.
Pas tout ce dont le corps a besoin.
I understand you've run through the agent training program.
T'as essayé le programme d'entraînement ?
You know, I wrote that program.
J'ai conçu ce programme.
Here it comes.
Il remet ça.
- What did you think of her? - Of who?
- Elle t'a plu ? - Qui ?
The woman in the red dress. I designed her.
La femme en rouge. Je l'ai créée.
She doesn't talk very much...
Elle est pas très causante...
...but if you'd like to meet her, I can arrange a more personal milieu.
mais si ça te dit, je te matérialise ça.
The digital pimp hard at work.
Le mac du numérique !
Pay no attention to these hypocrites, Neo.
N'écoute pas ces hypocrites.
To deny our own impulses...
Renier nos pulsions...
...is to deny the very thing that makes us human.
c'est renier ce qui fait de nous des humains.
Dozer, when you're done...
Dozer, quand t'as fini...
...bring the ship up to broadcast depth.
direction palier d'émission.
We're going in.
On va y entrer.
I'm taking Neo to see her.
J'emmène Neo la voir.
See who?
Qui ?
The Oracle.
L'Oracle.
Everyone please observe...
Respectez les signaux...
...the "fasten seat belt" and "no smoking" signs are on.
"attachez vos ceintures" et "défense de fumer".
Sit back and enjoy your flight.
L'équipage vous souhaite un bon voyage.
We're in.
On y est.
We'll be back in an hour.
On revient dans une heure.
Unbelievable...
Incroyable.
...isn't it?
Pas vrai ?
- God! - What?
- Ça alors ! - Quoi ?
I used to eat there.
Je venais manger là.
Really good noodles.
Des nouilles excellentes.
I have these memories from my life.
J'ai plein de souvenirs.
None of them happened.
Aucun ne s'est vraiment passé.
What does that mean?
Ça veut dire quoi ?
That the Matrix cannot tell you who you are.
La Matrice ignore qui tu es.
But an oracle can?
L'Oracle le sait ?
That's different.
C'est pas pareil.
Did you go to her?
Tu l'as consultée ?
Yes.
Oui.
What did she tell you?
Elle t'a dit quoi ?
She told me...
Elle m'a dit...
What?
Quoi ?
We're here.
C'est ici.
So is this the same oracle that made...
C'est le même oracle que celui qui a fait...
...the prophecy?
la prophétie ?
Yes. She's very old. She's been with us since the beginning.
Elle est âgée, et nous soutient depuis le début.
- The beginning? - Of the Resistance.
Le début ?
And she knows what? Everything?
Et elle sait quoi ? Tout ?
She would say she knows enough.
Elle dirait en savoir assez.
And she's never wrong.
Et avoir toujours raison.
Try not to think of it in terms of right and wrong.
Débarrasse-toi des notions de vrai et de faux.
She is a guide, Neo.
C'est notre mentor.
She can help you to find the path.
Elle t'aidera à trouver le chemin.
She helped you?
Elle t'a aidé ?
What did she tell you?
Elle t'a dit quoi ?
That I would find the One.
Que je trouverai l'Elu.
I told you I can only show you the door.
Je te montre la porte.
You have to walk through it.
A toi de la franchir.
Hello, Neo.
Bonjour, Neo.
You're right on time.
Tu es à l'heure.
Make yourself at home, Morpheus. Neo, come with me.
Installe-toi, Morpheus. Viens avec moi.
These are the other Potentials.
Ce sont les autres Potentiels.
You can wait here.
Attends ici.
Do not try and bend the spoon.
N'essaie pas de tordre la cuillère.
That's impossible.
C'est impossible.
Instead, only try to realize the truth.
Essaie plutôt de prendre conscience de la vérité.
What truth?
Quelle vérité ?
There is no spoon.
La cuillère n'existe pas.
There is no spoon?
Elle n'existe pas ?
Then you'll see that it is not the spoon that bends. It is only yourself.
Alors, tu comprendras qu'elle ne se tord pas, c'est juste toi.
The Oracle will you see now.
L'Oracle va te recevoir.
I know you're Neo.
Je sais, tu es Neo.
Be right with you.
J'arrive.
- You're the Oracle? - Bingo.
C'est vous, l'Oracle ?
Not quite what you were expecting, right?
Tu ne t'attendais pas à ça, pas vrai ?
Almost done.
C'est bientôt prêt.
Smell good, don't they?
Ça sent bon, non ?
I'd ask you to sit down...
Je sais que tu préfères...
...but you're not going to anyway.
rester debout.
- And don't worry about the vase. - What vase?
Et tant pis pour le vase.
That vase.
Celui-là.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
I said, don't worry about it.
Ne t'en fais pas.
I'll get one of my kids to fix it.
Un des gosses le recollera.
How did you know?
Vous aviez deviné ?
What's really going to bake your noodle later on is...
Ce qui va vraiment te faire gamberger, c'est :
...would you still have broken it if I hadn't said anything?
"est-ce que tu l'aurais cassé si j'avais rien dit ?"
You're cuter than I thought.
T'es plus mignon que je croyais.
I can see why she likes you.
Normal qu'elle en pince pour toi.
Who?
Qui ?
Not too bright, though.
Pas très dégourdi, par contre.
You know why Morpheus brought you to see me.
Tu sais pourquoi tu es ici ?
So...
Alors ?
...what do you think?
A ton avis ?
Do you think you are the One?
Tu crois être l'Elu ?
I don't know.
J'en sais rien.
You know what that means?
Tu en connais le sens ?
It's Latin.
C'est du latin.
Means, "Know thyself."
Ça signifie : "Connais-toi toi-même".
I'll let you in on a little secret.
Je vais te dire un secret.
Being the One is just like being in love.
Etre l'Elu, c'est comme être amoureux.
No one can tell you you're in love. You just know it...
Personne ne peut le deviner. On le ressent...
...through and through.
de part en part...
Balls to bones.
des couilles jusqu'aux os.
...I'd better have a look at you.
Je vais t'examiner.
Open your mouth. Say, "Ah."
Ouvre la bouche, dis "ah".
Now I'm supposed to say, "Hmm, that's interesting, but..."
Maintenant, je devrais dire : "Très intéressant, mais...".
Then you say:
Et là, tu dis...
But what?
Mais quoi ?
But you already know what I'm going to tell you.
Mais tu sais déjà ce que je vais répondre.
- I'm not the One. - Sorry, kid.
Je ne suis pas l'Elu.
You got the gift...
Tu en as l'étoffe.
...but it looks like you're waiting for something.
Mais tu restes dans l'expectative.
What?
Quoi ?
Your next life, maybe. Who knows?
Dans une autre vie, peut-être. Qui sait ?
That's the way these things go.
Ce sont des choses qui arrivent.
- What's funny? - Morpheus.
Pourquoi tu ris ?
He almost had me convinced.
Il a failli me convaincre.
I know.
Je sais.
Poor Morpheus.
Pauvre Morpheus.
Without him, we're lost.
Sans lui, nous sommes perdus.
What do you mean, "without him"?
Comment ça "sans lui" ?
Are you sure you want to hear this?
Tu veux vraiment savoir ?
Morpheus believes in you, Neo.
Morpheus croit en toi, Neo.
And no one, not you, not even me...
Et personne, ni toi, ni moi...
...can convince him otherwise.
ne pouvons le persuader du contraire.
He believes it so blindly...
Comme il y croit dur comme fer...
...that he's going to sacrifice his life to save yours.
il sacrifiera sa vie pour sauver la tienne.
You're going to have to make a choice.
Tu seras obligé de faire un choix.
In the one hand, you'll have Morpheus' life.
D'un côté, il y aura la vie de Morpheus...
And in the other hand, you'll have your own.
et de l'autre, ta propre vie.
One of you is going to die.
L'un de vous deux mourra.
Which one will be up to you.
Lequel ? Ce sera à toi de décider.
I'm sorry, kiddo. I really am.
Je suis désolée. Vraiment.
You have a good soul.
Tu as une âme généreuse.
And I hate giving good people bad news.
Ça me coûte de t'annoncer ça.
Don't worry about it.
Ne t'en fais pas.
As soon as you step outside that door...
Dès que tu auras franchi la porte...
...you'll start feeling better.
tu commenceras à te sentir mieux.
You'll remember you don't believe in any of this fate crap.
Tu te rappelleras que tu ne crois pas à ces foutaises.
You're in control of your own life.
C'est toi qui diriges ta vie...
Remember?
t'as pas oublié ?
Here...
Tiens.
...take a cookie.
Prends un cookie.
I promise, by the time you're done eating it...
Dès que tu l'auras fini, je te le promets...
...you'll feel right as rain.
tu te porteras comme un charme.
What was said...
Ce qui a été dit...
...was for you...
ne regarde que toi...
...and for you alone.
et toi seul.
They're on the way.
Ils arrivent.
What is that?
C'est quoi ?
What did you just say?
Quoi ?
Nothing. Just dj vu.
Une impression de déjà-vu.
- What did you see? - What happened?
Qu'est-ce que tu as vu ?
A black cat went past us...
Un chat noir est passé...
...then another just like it.
puis un 2ème, identique.
Was it the same cat?
C'était le même chat ?
- I'm not sure. - Switch, Apoc.
Je suis pas sûr.
What is it?
C'est quoi ?
A dj vu is usually a glitch in the Matrix when they change something.
Un bug qui se produit s'ils modifient la Matrice.
Oh, my God.
Mon Dieu.
Let's go.
Allons-y !
They cut the hard line. It's a trap! Get out!
C'est un piège. Filez !
- That's what they changed. - We're trapped.
Voilà ce qu'ils ont modifié. On est bloqués.
Be calm. Give me your phone.
Du calme. Passe-moi le téléphone.
They'll be able to track it.
Ils vont le repérer.
We have no choice.
On n'a pas le choix.
Find a structural drawing of this building. Find it fast.
Trouve un plan du bâtiment. Fais vite !
- Got it! - I need the main wet-wall.
- Je l'ai. - Repère les canalisations.
Eighth floor.
Au huitième !
They're on the eighth floor.
Ils sont au huitième étage.
Switch, straight ahead.
Switch, tout droit !
I hope the Oracle gave you some good news.
L'Oracle t'a motivé, j'espère.
Now left. That's it.
A gauche. Vous y êtes.
Good.
Bien.
Where are they?
Où sont-ils ?
They're in the walls.
Ils sont dans les murs.
In the walls!
Dans les murs !
It's an agent!
C'est un agent !
You must get Neo out!
Fais sortir Neo.
He's all that matters!
C'est lui qui compte.
- No, Morpheus! Don't! - Trinity, go!
Non, ne fais pas ça !
- We can't leave him! - We have to!
- On va pas le laisser. - Si !
The great Morpheus. We meet at last.
Le grand Morpheus. On se rencontre enfin !
And you are?
Vous êtes ?
A Smith.
Smith.
Agent Smith.
Agent Smith.
You all look the same to me.
Vous vous ressemblez tous.
Take him.
Emmenez-le.
- Operator. - I need an exit, fast.
- Opérateur. - Fais-moi sortir.
There was an accident. Goddamn car accident.
On a eu un accident de bagnole.
All of a sudden, boom.
Et tout à coup, boum !
Somebody up there still likes me.
Dieu tient encore à moi.
I got you.
Je t'ai localisé.
Just get me out of here fast.
Fais-moi sortir d'ici, vite !
Nearest exit, Franklin and Erie. An old TV repair shop.
A Franklin et Erie, un réparateur de télés.
Right.
C'est ça.
- Operator. - Tank, it's me.
- Opérateur. - C'est moi.
Is Morpheus alive?
Morpheus est vivant ?
Is Morpheus alive, Tank?
Morpheus est vivant, Tank ?
Yes. They're moving him. I don't know where.
Ils l'ont emmené. Je sais pas où.
He's alive. We need an exit.
Il est vivant. On veut rentrer.
You're not far from Cypher.
Rejoignez Cypher.
- Cypher? - I know.
- Cypher ? - Je sais.
- I sent him to Franklin and Erie. - Got it.
- Sur Franklin et Erie. - Pigé.
Got him.
C'est lui.
Where are they?
Où sont-ils ?
Making the call.
Je les appelle.
Good.
Super.
You first.
Toi d'abord, Neo.
Shit!
Merde !
I don't know. It just went dead.
On n'entend plus rien.
Cypher? Where's Tank?
Cypher ? Où est Tank ?
You know...
Tu sais...
...for a long time...
pendant très longtemps...
...I thought I was in love with you.
j'ai cru que j'étais amoureux de toi.
I used to dream about you.
Je rêvais de toi.
You're a beautiful woman, Trinity.
Tu es vraiment très belle.
Too bad things had to turn out this way.
Dommage que les choses aient mal tourné.
You killed them.
Tu les as tués !
- What? - Oh, God.
- Quoi ? - Mon Dieu.
I'm tired, Trinity.
J'en ai assez, Trinity.
I'm tired of this war...
J'en ai marre de cette guerre...
...tired of fighting. I'm tired of this ship...
marre de me battre, du vaisseau...
...of being cold, of eating the same goddamn goop every day.
d'avoir froid, de manger la même mixture tous les jours.
But most of all...
Et par-dessus tout...
...I'm tired of that jackoff and all of his bullshit.
j'en ai marre de ce con et de ses bobards.
Surprise, asshole!
Surprise, ducon !
I bet you never saw this coming...
Je parie que t'avais pas prévu ça...
...did you?
pas vrai ?
God, I wish I could be there...
Ce que j'aimerais être là...
...when they break you.
quand ils te feront la peau.
I wish I could walk in just when it happens...
Ça me plairait d'arriver à ce moment-là.
...so right then...
Alors...
...you'd know it was me.
tu saurais que c'était moi.
You gave them Morpheus.
Tu l'as donné.
He lied to us, Trinity.
Il nous a menti.
He tricked us!
Il nous a roulés.
If you had told us the truth...
Si tu nous avais dit la vérité...
...we would've told you to shove that red pill up your ass!
on t'aurait dit de te foutre ta pilule au cul !
That is not true, Cypher. He set us free.
C'est faux. Il nous a libérés.
"Free." You call this free?
"Libérés" ?
All I do is what he tells me to do.
Je ne fais qu'obéir à ses ordres.
If I had to choose between that and the Matrix...
Si je devais choisir entre ça et la Matrice...
...I choose the Matrix.
je choisirais la Matrice.
The Matrix isn't real.
Elle est fictive.
I disagree, Trinity.
Je ne suis pas d'accord.
I think the Matrix...
Je crois que la Matrice...
...can be more real than this world.
peut être plus réelle que ce monde.
All I do is pull the plug here.
Ici, je débranche juste une prise.
But there...
Mais là-bas...
...you have to watch Apoc die.
tu verras mourir Apoc.
- Welcome to the real world. - But you're out, Cypher.
Bienvenue dans le monde réel !
- You can't go back. - That's what you think.
- Tu ne pourras pas revenir. - C'est ce que tu crois.
They'll reinsert my body.
Mon corps sera réinséré.
I go back to sleep. When I wake up, I won't remember a thing.
Je m'endormirai et à mon réveil, j'aurai tout oublié.
By the way...
Au fait...
...if you have anything important to say to Switch...
si t'as quelque chose de capital à dire à Switch...
...say it now.
c'est le moment.
- No, please don't. - Not like this.
Non, je t'en prie.
Too late.
Trop tard.
Don't hate me, Trinity.
Ne m'en veux pas, Trinity.
I'm just a messenger.
Je ne suis qu'un messager.
And right now, I'm going to prove it to you.
Et je vais te le prouver sur-le-champ.
If Morpheus was right...
Si Morpheus ne s'est pas trompé...
...there's no way I can pull this plug.
cette prise me résistera.
If Neo's the One...
Si Neo est l'Elu...
...then there'd have to be...
alors, il se produira...
...some kind of a miracle to stop me.
un miracle qui m'empêchera de l'ôter.
Right?
Pas vrai ?
I mean, how can he be the One...
Comment peut-il être l'Elu...
...if he's dead?
s'il est mort ?
You never did answer me before...
J'ai toujours voulu savoir...
...if you bought into Morpheus' bullshit.
si t'avais gobé les bobards de Morpheus.
Come on. All I want is a little yes or no.
Réponds juste par oui ou par non.
Look into his eyes...
Regarde-le dans les yeux...
...those big, pretty eyes...
ses beaux yeux...
...and tell me...
et réponds-moi...
...yes...
oui...
...or no.
ou non.
- Yes. - No!
Oui.
I don't believe it.
J'y crois pas !
Believe it or not, you piece of shit, you're still going to burn!
Que tu le croies ou non, ordure, tu vas cramer !
You first.
Toi d'abord.
- You're hurt. - I'll be all right.
Tu es blessé.
Dozer?
Et Dozer ?
Have you ever stood and stared at it?
Ne l'avez-vous jamais contemplée...
Marveled at its beauty...
n'avez-vous jamais été ébloui par sa beauté...
...its genius?
son ingéniosité ?
Billions of people...
Des milliards de gens...
...just living out their lives.
vivent leurs petites vies...
Oblivious.
dans l'ignorance.
Did you know that the first Matrix...
Saviez-vous que la première matrice...
...was designed to be a perfect human world where none suffered...
avait pour dessein de créer un monde dépourvu de souffrances...
...where everyone would be happy.
où tous seraient heureux ?
It was a disaster.
Ce fut un désastre.
No one would accept the program. Entire crops were lost.
Le programme n'était pas accepté. On a perdu des récoltes.
Some believe that...
Certains pensaient...
...we lacked the programming language to describe your perfect world.
qu'on n'était pas à même de créer l'encodage de votre monde parfait.
But I believe that...
Mais je crois que...
...as a species...
votre espèce...
...human beings define their reality through misery...
le genre humain, se satisfait d'une réalité faite de malheur...
...and suffering.
et de souffrances.
So the perfect world was a dream...
Le monde parfait était un rêve...
...that your primitive cerebrum kept trying to wake up from.
que votre cerveau primitif s'évertuait à fuir.
Which is why the Matrix was redesigned to this.
C'est pour cela que la Matrice fut remaniée.
The peak...
L'apogée...
...of your civilization.
de votre civilisation.
I say, "your civilization"...
Je dis bien de votre civilisation...
...because when we started thinking for you, it became our civilization...
car depuis que votre pensée est nôtre, c'est devenu notre civilisation...
...which is, of course, what this is all about.
ce qui est le coeur du problème.
Evolution, Morpheus.
L'évolution, Morpheus.
Evolution.
L'évolution.
Like the dinosaur.
Comme le dinosaure.
Look out that window.
Regardez par la fenêtre.
You had your time.
Vous avez fait votre temps.
The future is our world, Morpheus.
L'avenir, c'est notre monde, Morpheus.
The future is our time.
L'avenir, c'est notre temps à nous.
There could be a problem.
Il y a un problème.
- What are they doing to him? - They're breaking into his mind.
- Ils lui font quoi ? - Ils pénètrent son esprit.
It's like hacking a computer. All it takes is time.
Ça prend du temps.
How much time?
Beaucoup ?
Depends on the mind. But eventually, it'll crack...
Ça dépend de l'esprit. Il finira par craquer...
...and his alpha patterns will change from this to this.
et son rythme alpha passera de ça à ça.
When it does, he'll tell them anything they want to know.
Alors, Morpheus leur dira tout ce qu'ils veulent.
What do they want?
Comme quoi ?
The leader of every ship is given codes to Zion's mainframe computer.
Chaque commandant connaît les codes de l'ordinateur central de Zion.
If an agent got the codes and got into Zion's mainframe...
Si un agent accède à ce serveur...
...they could destroy us. We can't let that happen.
il peut nous détruire. Il faut les en empêcher.
Trinity, Zion's more important than me...
Zion compte bien plus que moi...
...or you...
toi...
...or even Morpheus.
ou même Morpheus.
There has to be something we can do.
Trouvons une solution.
There is. We pull the plug.
Il y en a une. On le débranche.
You're going to kill him?
Tu veux le tuer ?
Kill Morpheus?
Tuer Morpheus ?
We don't have a choice.
On n'a pas le choix.
Never send a human to do a machine's job.
Un homme ne peut se substituer à une machine.
If the insider has failed...
Si l'informateur a échoué...
...they'll sever the connection as soon as possible, unless...
ils le déconnecteront, sauf si...
They're dead. In either case...
S'il les a tués. Cependant...
We have no choice. Continue as planned. Deploy the sentinels.
Nous devons faire comme prévu. Déployez les sentinelles...
Immediately.
vite !
Morpheus, you were more than a leader to us.
Morpheus, tu étais bien plus qu'un chef.
You were a father.
Tu étais...un père.
We'll miss you always.
Nous te regretterons.
I don't believe this is happening.
Je crois rêver.
- Neo, this has to be done. - Does it?
- On est obligés. - Vraiment ?
I don't know.
Je ne sais pas...
- This can't be just coincidence. - What?
C'est pas une coïncidence.
The Oracle.
L'Oracle...
She told me this would happen.
elle me l'avait prédit.
She told me that I would have to make a choice.
Elle m'a dit que je devrais faire un choix.
What choice?
Quel choix ?
- What are you doing? - I'm going in.
Que fais-tu ?
- No, you're not. - I have to.
Pas question.
Neo, Morpheus sacrificed himself so that we could get you out.
Morpheus s'est sacrifié pour qu'on te fasse sortir.
There is no way that you're going back in.
Tu n'y retourneras pas.
Morpheus did what he did because he believed I'm something I'm not.
Morpheus croyait que je suis ce que je ne suis pas.
I'm not the One, Trinity.
Je ne suis pas l'Elu.
- The Oracle hit me with that too. - No, you have to be.
- L'Oracle me l'a jeté à la tête. - Impossible.
I'm sorry, I'm not. I'm just another guy.
Désolé, je suis comme les autres.
No, Neo, that's not true.
Non, ce n'est pas vrai.
- It can't be true. - Why?
Ça ne se peut pas.
This is loco. They've got Morpheus in a military-controlled building.
T'es branque. Ce bâtiment est contrôlé par l'armée.
Even if you somehow got inside, those are agents holding him. Three of them.
Même si tu réussis à entrer, il est gardé par trois agents !
I want Morpheus back too, but what you're talking about is suicide.
Je veux que Morpheus revienne, mais c'est suicidaire.
That's what it looks like...
Ça en a tout l'air...
...but it's not.
mais ça ne l'est pas.
I can't explain to you why it's not.
Je ne peux pas vous l'expliquer.
Morpheus believed something, and he was ready to give his life for it.
Morpheus avait une certitude. Il était prêt à se sacrifier pour ça.
I understand that now. That's why I have to go.
C'est pour ça que je dois y aller.
- Why? - Because I believe in something.
Pourquoi ?
What?
Laquelle ?
I believe I can bring him back.
Je suis sûr de le ramener.
- What are you doing? - Going with you.
- Que fais-tu ? - Je viens.
- No, you're not. - "No"?
Pas question.
Let me tell you what I believe.
Je vais te dire ce que je crois.
Morpheus means more to me than he does to you.
Je tiens plus à Morpheus que toi.
I believe if you are serious about saving him, you will need my help.
Si tu veux le sauver, tu vas avoir besoin de mon aide.
And since I am the ranking officer...
Je suis ton supérieur.
...if you don't like it, I believe you can go to hell.
Si ça te déplaît, crève en enfer !
Because you aren't going anywhere else.
Parce que tu n'iras pas ailleurs.
Tank...
Tank...
...load us up.
charge-nous dans le programme.
I'd like to share a revelation that I've had...
J'aimerais vous faire part d'une révélation...
...during my time here.
que j'ai eue ici.
It came to me when I tried to classify your species...
Elle m'est apparue quand j'ai voulu classer votre espèce.
...and I realized...
Je me suis aperçu...
...that you're not actually mammals.
que vous n'étiez pas des mammifères.
Every mammal on this planet...
Les mammifères de cette planète...
...instinctively develops an equilibrium with the surrounding environment.
développent un équilibre naturel avec le milieu qui les entoure.
But you humans do not.
Pas les êtres humains.
You move to an area and you multiply...
Vous vous installez dans une région et vous vous multipliez...
...and multiply until every natural resource is consumed.
jusqu'à ce que vous ayez épuisé toutes les ressources naturelles.
The only way you can survive...
Et la seule façon de vous en sortir...
...is to spread to another area.
est d'aller vous propager ailleurs.
There is another organism on this planet...
Il existe un autre organisme sur cette planète...
...that follows the same pattern.
qui en fait de même.
Do you know what it is?
Savez-vous ce que c'est ?
A virus.
Un virus.
Human beings are a disease.
Les êtres humains sont une maladie...
A cancer of this planet.
le cancer de cette planète.
You are a plague.
Vous êtes un fléau...
And we...
et nous sommes...
...are the cure.
le remède.
Okay, so what do you need?
T'as besoin de quoi ?
Besides a miracle.
A part d'un miracle ?
Guns.
D'armes !
Lots of guns.
Plein d'armes !
No one has ever done anything like this.
Personne n'a osé faire ça.
That's why it's going to work.
C'est pour ça que ça va marcher.
Why isn't the serum working?
Pourquoi le sérum n'agit pas ?
Perhaps we're asking the wrong questions.
On ne pose pas les bonnes questions.
Leave me with him.
Laissez-nous seuls.
Now.
Maintenant !
Hold on, Morpheus.
Tiens bon, Morpheus.
They're coming for you. They're coming.
Ils viennent te sauver. Ils arrivent.
Can you hear me, Morpheus?
Vous m'entendez, Morpheus ?
I'm going to be honest...
Je vais être franc...
...with you.
avec vous.
...hate...
J'exècre...
...this place...
cet endroit...
...this zoo...
ce zoo...
...this prison...
cette prison...
...this reality, whatever you want to call it.
cette réalité, appelez-la comme vous voudrez.
I can't stand it any longer.
Je ne la supporte plus.
It's the smell.
C'est son odeur...
If there is such a thing.
si les odeurs existent.
I feel saturated by it.
Elle me donne la nausée.
I can...
En bouche...
...taste...
j'ai le goût...
...your stink.
de votre puanteur.
And every time I do, I fear that I have somehow been infected by it.
Quand ça m'arrive, j'ai l'impression d'être contaminé.
It's repulsive.
C'est répugnant.
Isn't it?
Pas vrai ?
I must get out of here.
Je dois sortir d'ici.
I must get free.
Je dois me libérer.
And in this mind is the key.
Et dans ce cerveau, il y a la clef.
My key.
Ma clef !
Once Zion is destroyed, there is no need for me to be here.
Zion détruit, je n'ai plus rien à faire ici.
Do you understand?
Tu comprends ?
I need the codes.
J'ai besoin des codes.
I have to get inside Zion...
Je dois pénétrer dans Zion...
...and you have to tell me how.
et tu dois me dire comment faire.
You're going to tell me...
Tu vas me le dire...
...or you're going to die.
sinon tu mourras.
Please remove any metallic items you're carrying. Keys, loose change.
Débarrassez-vous des objets en métal. Clefs, monnaie...
Holy shit!
Putain de merde !
Backup. Send backup.
Des renforts !
Freeze!
Pas un geste !
What were you doing?
Que fais-tu ?
He doesn't know.
Il ne sait rien.
Know what?
A quel sujet ?
I think they're trying to save him.
Ils tentent de le sauver.
There is no spoon.
La cuillère n'existe pas.
Find them and destroy them!
Trouvez-les et tuez-les !
We're under attack!
Nous sommes attaqués !
Help!
Aide-moi.
Only human.
Tu n'es qu'un humain.
Dodge this.
Evite ça !
- How did you do that? - Do what?
- Comment t'as fait ? - Quoi ?
You moved like they do. I've never seen anyone move that fast.
Tu bouges comme eux. Personne n'est aussi rapide.
It wasn't fast enough.
Pas encore assez.
Can you fly that thing?
Tu sais piloter ça ?
Not yet.
Pas encore.
I need a pilot program for a B-212 helicopter.
J'ai besoin de savoir piloter un B-212.
Hurry.
Dépêche-toi !
Let's go.
Allons-y !
Morpheus, get up. Get up, get up.
Morpheus, lève-toi.
He's not going to make it.
Il n'y arrivera pas.
Got you.
Je te tiens !
I knew it.
Je le savais.
He's the One.
Il est l'Elu.
Do you believe it now, Trinity?
Tu es convaincue, maintenant ?
The Oracle.
L'Oracle...
- She told me... - She told you...
- Elle m'a... - Elle t'a dit...
...what you needed to hear.
ce que tu voulais entendre.
That's all.
C'est tout.
Sooner or later you'll realize, just as I did...
Tôt ou tard, tu comprendras, comme moi...
...there's a difference between knowing the path...
qu'on peut connaître le chemin...
...and walking the path.
ou l'emprunter.
- It's good to hear your voice. - We need an exit.
- Heureux de vous entendre. - Trouve une issue.
Got one ready. Subway station, State and Balboa.
J'en ai une, au métro State et Balboa.
- We have their position. - Sentinels are standing by.
On a leur position.
Order the strike.
Donne l'ordre d'attaquer.
They're not out yet.
Ils ne sont pas encore sortis.
You first, Morpheus.
Toi d'abord, Morpheus.
Neo, I want to tell you something...
J'ai quelque chose à te dire...
...but I'm afraid of what it could mean if I do.
mais j'ai peur de ta réaction.
Everything the Oracle told me has come true.
Tout ce que l'Oracle m'a prédit s'est réalisé.
Everything but this.
Tout excepté ça.
But what?
Quoi ?
- What happened? - An agent.
- C'était quoi ? - Un agent.
- Send me back. - I can't.
Renvoie-moi là-bas.
Mr. Anderson.
M. Anderson...
Run, Neo. Run.
Fuis, Neo. Fuis !
What is he doing?
Que fait-il ?
He's beginning to believe.
Il commence à croire.
You're empty.
Vous n'avez plus rien.
So are you.
Vous non plus.
I'm going to enjoy watching you die...
Je vais me délecter à vous regarder mourir...
...Mr. Anderson.
M. Anderson.
Jesus, he's killing him.
Il le massacre.
He's gonna make it.
Il va s'en sortir.
Oh, shit!
Oh, merde !
They're inside.
Elles sont entrées.
Hurry, Neo.
Vite, Neo !
It can't be.
Ça ne se peut pas.
Now, get up.
Relève-toi.
How?
Je rêve !